MONISH KUMAR MUTHUVIJAYAN

phone: +1 469-803-2841

email: monishkumarm@gmail.com

blog: medium.com/@monishkumar

portfolio: http://www.monishkumar.me

about me

Computer science graduate with 2.5 years experience in user experience design, interaction design, mobile app design and front-end development. Passionate designer with a strong desire to help build and ship user-centeric products. Adept at research, ideation, ux design, wireframing, prototyping and microinteractions.

skills

User Research, Usability Testing, User Experience Design, User Stories, Persona Development, Storyboarding, Interaction Design, Microinteractions. Wireframing, Prototyping, Agile Methodologies, UI & App Design, UI Development

tools

Sketch, Principle, Invision, Git, Zeplin, Balsamiq, Marvel, Adobe Creative Suite(Ps, Ai)

programming

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS, ExpectJS, Karma, Mocha, PrimeFaces, JSF

ux education

masters coursework

- UI Design & Development
- Human Computer Interaction
- Web Development

honors

- Scholarship of Merit in undergraduate studies
- Jonsson School Dean Scholarship in graduate studies
- Winner of Allcal UX Challenge

education

M. S - Computer Science (HCI)

Aug 2014 - Aug 2016

The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX, USA

B. Tech - Information Technology

Aug 2008 - May 2012

SSN College of Engineering, Chennai, India

experiences

Product Designer

Ford Motor Company

Oct 2016 - Present

skills: User Interviews, Wireframes, Storyboarding, Prototyping, Design Specs, Front-End Development, Programming, End to End Design

tools: Sketch, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, JSF, PrimeFaces

role: • Conduct user interviews with Business & Users to understand their needs.

• Develop Wireframes(Sketch), code prototypes and deliver front-end code.

Product Designer

Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

skills: Usability Testing, Wireframes, Prototyping, Information Architecture, User Experience Design, Visual Design, Front-End Development, Programming

tools: Sketch, Marvel, Invision, Zeplin, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

- role: Conduct Usability Testing and User Testing to gather user feedback.
 - Redesign app across iOS, Android and Web to make the app simple, satisfy user and business goals, and improve user retention rate.

UI/UX Intern

Cityon Systems

Aug 2015 - Jan 2016

skills: Research, Wireframes, Prototyping, Front-End Development, Programming

tools: Sketch, Marvel, Visual Studio, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, .NET and C#

- role: Work independently on internal project management tool, design and implement new features like a calendar view for all tasks for better UX.
 - Design and Implement new features like cost calculator on company website to help convert visitors to potential customers.

User Experience Designer

Fonearena

Jul 2013 - Jul 2014

skills: Competitor Analysis, Market Research, User Research, Wireframes, Prototyping, Design Specs, Front-End Development, Programming

tools: Balsamiq, Adobe Creative Suite, Axure, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

role: • Conduct User Research Surveys & Interview stakeholders for new features.

• Sketch wireframes and deliver Hi-Def prototypes to developers.

Availability - Immediate